Finding Aid for H. Beach Carpenter papers, 1928-1955
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
H. Beach Carpenter papers 1928-1955
Carpenter, H. Beach (Hiram Beach), 1892-1955.
1 linear foot
85868 Aa 2
University of Michigan alumnus; correspondence and other papers concerning alumni fund-raising matters, reunion activities of the class of 1914, and other university matters.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Mrs. H. Beach Carpenter (donor no. 3177 ) and came to the library in 1956.
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
H. Beach Carpenter was a graduate of the University of Michigan, class of 1914. He later received a law degree and became a vice president of the American Sugar Company. Carpenter was also involved in alumni activities and in various university related organizations and projects, notably Michigamua and the Michigan Phoenix Project.
The Carpenter collection includes correspondence and other papers concerning alumni fund-raising matters, reunion activities of the class of 1914, development of the Michigan Phoenix Project, and activities of the Michigamua.
Subjects:
Michigamua.; Michigan Memorial Phoenix Project.; University of Michigan--Alumni and alumnae.; University of Michigan. Class of 1914.; University of Michigan Club of New York.; Carpenter, H. Beach (Hiram Beach), 1892-1955.
- Correspondence
  - 1928 (Box 1)
  - 1929 (Box 1)
  - 1930, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - 1931 (Box 1)
  - 1932 (Box 1)
  - 1933-1934 (Box 1)
  - 1935-1936 (Box 1)
  - 1937 (Box 1)
  - 1938 (Box 1)
  - 1939 (Box 1)
  - 1940-1941 (Box 1)
  - 1942-1945 (Box 1)
  - 1946 (Box 1)
  - 1947 (Box 1)
  - 1948 (Box 1)
  - 1949 (Box 1)
  - 1950-1951 (Box 1)
  - 1952 (Box 1)
  - 1953 (Box 1)
  - 1954-1955 (Box 1)
- Topical files
  - Activities of Michigamua, 1950-1951 (Box 1)
  - Centennial celebration of the University, 1936-1937 (Box 1)
  - Annual alumni club dinner in New York, 1930 (Box 1)
  - Faculty Salary Endowment Fund
    - 1930 (Box 1)
    - 1931-1943 (Box 1)
  - Michigan Memorial-Phoenix Project, 1949-1951, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - First Alumni District Convention, 1933, 3 folders (Box 1)